She gave and gave, until she had nothing left to give
The Rose is a drama, music, romance film directed by Mark Rydell.
Rock-and-roll singer Mary Rose Foster's romantic relationships and mental health
are continuously imperilled by the demands of life on the road.
Mary Rose Foster, played by Bette Midler.
Rudge Campbell, played by Alan Bates.
Huston Dyer, played by Frederic Forrest.
Billy Ray, played by Harry Dean Stanton.
Dennis, played by Barry Primus.
Mal, played by David Keith.
The Rose is a 1979 American musical drama film directed by Mark Rydell, and starring Bette Midler,
Alan Bates, Frederic Forrest, Harry Dean Stanton, Barry Primus, and David Keith.
Loosely based on the life of Janis Joplin, the film follows self-destructive rock star Mary Rose Foster in the late 1960s, who
struggles to cope with the pressures of her career and the demands of her ruthless business manager Rudge Campbell.
Originally titled Pearl (Janis Joplin's nickname and the title of her last album), the film's screenplay was
revised and fictionalized after the Joplin family declined to allow producers the rights to her story.
The Rose was nominated for four Academy Awards at the 52nd Academy Awards (1980), including Best Actress in a Leading Role (Bette
Midler, in her screen debut), Best Actor in a Supporting Role (Frederic Forrest), Best Film Editing and Best Sound.
Midler performed the soundtrack album for the film, and its
title track became one of her biggest hit singles.
The film explores themes of singer, drugs, rock band, self destructiveness.
The tone is emotional.